SAMANTHA CRESPO

Richland, WA | 469.686.07650 | Email | LinkedIn | GitHub | Blog

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

With 8 years experience in sales and customer service, I bring my soft skills in communication and problem solving abilities. I started to code because I like the challenge of tackling problems that triggers my perseverance to achieve success which is delivering a tangible and creative project to tech companies. I'm excited for the opportunity to role model to other women that we can be a leader in tech despite being a minority. As a software engineer I'm proficient in JavaScript, React, HTML/CSS, SQL, Ruby and Rails with ~800 hours of training and more being added on daily.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Full-stack Development, JavaScript, React.js, Redux.js, Ruby/Ruby on Rails, Active Record, OOP, SQLite, PostgreSQL, HTML, CSS, Git/GitHub, REST API

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

EGG RECIPES - https://github.com/samkcrespo/Phase2-Project.git

JavaScript, React, HTML, CSS

- Developed an application that features recipes that can be made using eggs. App focused on user experience, with attention to UI & accessibility.
- Features: React.js, React Routing, RESTful API, JSON database

PET MATCHER- https://github.com/samkcrespo/Phase-3-Project-Front-end-.git

Ruby, JavaScript, React, CSS, SQLite

- Developed an application that shows adoptable pets, as well as the ability to view & process adoption applications.
- Features: React.js, React Routing, Ruby, RESTful API

VOLUNTEER NETWORK-https://github.com/samkcrespo/Phase-4-react-rails-api-project-backend

Ruby, JavaScript, React.js, CSS, SQLite

- Developed an application to post and volunteer for local events in Denver, CO. Users must log in, and can view upcoming events, resign from events, and create new events
- Features: React.js, React Routing, Ruby, RESTful API

EXPERIENCE

Leasing Director | Gaines Investment Trust | Plano, TX | 2/2020 - 2/2022

- Responsible for leasing 368-unit residential property, closing at 98-99% occupancy each month.
- Supported property manager with property improvements, resident retention, notices, and communication
- Managed & Marketed the 'Preferred Employer Program' to bring in ~4 additional residents per month
- Solved ~4 resident problems per day

Assistant Store Manager | Sprint | Plano, TX | 4/2017 - 5/2019

- Increased customer satisfaction by resolving equipment, network and troubleshooting issues for existing and new customers.
- Met and managed sales quotes of ~35 devices per month
- Awarded top seller of my region twice in a row [May 2017, June 2017]

Store Manager | Secondhand Sports | The Colony, TX | 4/2012 - 3/2017

- Appraised & purchased new and gently used sporting goods equipment.
- Reviewed and improved organizational effectiveness by developing processes, overseeing employees and establishing a highly motivational work environment
- Oversaw day to day operations, assign weekly performance goals and accomplish my own goals set forth by CEO
- Managed team of 4-6 people, developed weekly schedules & organized team meetings

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Certificate – Flatiron, Remote 7/2022

- Technologies used: React, jQuery, Bootstrap, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, APIs, GitHub, Ruby, Sinatra, Ruby on Rails
- Skills learned: Full-stack Development, Software Development, REST API, Debugging, Test-Driven Development,

Coursework towards an Associate of Science Degree - Collin County Community College, Plano, TX 1/2013 - 5/2013